DC Special Libraries Association 014
People's Archive, MLK Library
D.C. Special Libraries Association Records
1940-1985
People's Archive, MLK Library
District of Columbia Special Library Association
014
5 Linear feet
13 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: General topics, 1940-1966 (1.75 linear ft.) This series contains topical files including community service activities (1944-1955), continuing education, American Society for Information Science - Special Library Association merger, professional standards, recruitment, government relations, the Miriam Vance Lecture, and information technology issues. The folders are arranged alphabetically by topic. Series 2: Committee files, 1943-1965 (3.5 linear ft.) This series contains records maintained by committees of D.C. Special Library Association (DCSLA). It includes committee reports, correspondence, internal memoranda, budgets, and meeting minutes. This series also contains DCSLA's by-laws, constitution, and procedures manual. Some of the committees represented are Continuing Education, Government Relations, Hospitality, Nominations, Employment, Membership, Professional Activities and Publicity. Folders are arranged alphabetically by name of the committee. Series 3: Group files, 1941-1966 (1 linear ft.) This series contains files that document the activities of member subgroups formed by DCSLA to address specific issues and concerns of members by subject specialties. The series contains correspondence, group meeting minutes, and special reports. Specialties covered by the files include military, fine arts, geography, biological sciences, and business. The folders are arranged alphabetically by group. Series 4: Newsletters, 1943-1949, 1956, 1988 (.5 linear ft.) This series contains editions of Notes, the newsletter of DCSLA.
Biographical / Historical
The Special Libraries Association (SLA) was founded in 1909 to promote and support librarians working in special library settings. The Washington, D.C. Chapter was the twentieth to be formed on October 25, 1940.
Custodial History
Records of the D.C. Special Libraries Association (DCSLA) were donated by various members and officers of the since 1988.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes annual reports, correspondence, by-laws, D.C. Special Library Association constitutions (1940-1966), maps, biographical information, a procedures manual, photographs, and planning reports. It also contains records of committee work, member groups, and editions of the chapter newsletter Notes.
Libraries; Librarians; Associations, institutions, etc; Photographs; Organizational Records; Correspondence
- Series 1: General topics, 1940-1966
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains topical files. A sampling of subjects covered by the records includes community service activities (1944-1955), continuing education, ASIS-SLA merger, professional standards, recruitment, government relations, the Miriam Vance Lecture, and information technology issues. The folders are arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Annual reports of President, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ASIS-SLA Merger, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Awards, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Boundary issue, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bylaws, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chapter meetings, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Continuing education, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Executive Board and Advisory Council, 1941-1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Executive Board and Advisory Council, 1970-1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Guide to meeting places, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Logan Cowgill Memorial Fund, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Metropolitan Washington Council of Governments, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Miriam Vance Lecture Fund, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Obituaries, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Personnel Questionnaire, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Treasurer reports, 1944-1979 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Series 2: Committee files, 1943-1965
  This series contains records maintained by committees of DCSLA. It includes committee reports, correspondence, internal memoranda, budgets, and meeting minutes. This series also contains DCSLA's by-laws, constitution, and procedures manual. Some of the committees represented are Continuing Education, Government Relations, Hospitality, Nominations, Employment, Membership, Professional Activities and Publicity. Folders are arranged alphabetically by name of the committee.
  - Archives, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Auditing, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Book buying, 1945-1949 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Book Fair, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Budget, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Budgetary standard operating procedure, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - By-Laws—SLA Washington Chapter, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Chapter Notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Chapter officers, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Chapter Procedure Manual, Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Community Service, 1944-1955 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Constitution, 1940-1966 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Consultation, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Continuing education, Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Convention, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correlation of library statistics report, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Employment, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Government relations, Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Hospitality, Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Inter-Library cooperation, Undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Joint Spring Workshop, Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Long range planning, Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Membership, Undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Membership Directory and special publications, Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Networking project, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Nominations and elections, 1945-1976 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Nominations and elections, 1945-1976 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Placement, Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Professional activities, 1943-1959 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Professional activities, 1943-1959 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Professional Standards, Undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Program, 1941-1978 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Publicity, 1942-1952 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Publicity, 1942-1952 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Public relations, 1947-1959 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Recruitment, Undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Scholarship, Undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Social concerns, Undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Student Loan fund, Undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Series 3: Group files, 1941-1966
  This series contains files that document the activities of member subgroups formed by DCSLA to address the specific issues and concerns of members by subject specialties. The series contains correspondence, group meeting minutes, and special reports. Specialties covered by the files include military, fine arts, geography, biological sciences, and business. The folders are arranged alphabetically by group.
  - Biological sciences, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Business, 1943-1945 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Documentation, Undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Documentation, Undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Documentation, Undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Association Liaison, Undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Fine Arts, 1941-1952 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Geography and Map, 1941-1966 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Geography and Map, 1941-1966 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Geography and Map, 1941-1966 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Information Technology, Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Military, 1953-1965 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Military, 1953-1965 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Picture, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Science and Technology, 1941-19 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Social Science, 1941-19 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Transportation, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - University and College, 1943-1950 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Series 4: Newsletters, 1943-1949, 1956, 1988
  This series contains editions of Notes, the newsletter of DCSLA.
  - Chapter Notes, 1943-1988 (Box 13, Folder 1)